Preliminary Guide to the Helen Coley Nauts Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Helen Coley Nauts papers
1875-2000
MS 1785
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
117.5
(119 boxes)
The papers consist of patient files, correspondence, writings, subject files, and other materials documenting the careers of Helen Coley Nauts and her father, William Coley. The collection includes information regarding the use of "Coley toxins," a vaccine developed by Coley and promoted by Nauts, which has been used successfully in the treatment of cancer.
Nauts, Helen C. (Helen Coley), 1907-2001
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Phyllis Nauts, 2001.
Conditions Governing Access
The material is unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu. The request should outline the scope and purpose of the research project, why the researcher believes the material is relevant to their project, and contact information. If possible the request should also include a list of specific material of interest including collection, box, and folder numbers (or folder descriptions if folders are not numbered). The review may take several weeks.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series: I. Helen Coley Nauts Active Files. II. William B. Coley Medical Files. III. Cancer Research Institute Files. IV. Helen Coley Nauts Family Papers. V. William B. Coley Work Files and Family Papers. VI. Writings and Miscellaneous.
Biographical / Historical
Helen Coley Nauts was born September 2, 1907, in Sharon, Connecticut, to William Bradley and Alice (Lancaster) Coley. In 1953, she founded the Cancer Research Institute, largely to support research relating to the work of her father, a surgeon and cancer specialist who, prior to his death in 1936, developed an early form of immunotherapy as a method for treating cancer. To treat cancer patients, Dr. Coley administered "Coley toxins," a mixture of live bacteria intended to spark the body into producing its own defenses against the disease. Although Coley recorded many successes with his treatment, his work became overshadowed by radiation and chemotherapy. Through the Cancer Research Institute, Helen Coley Nauts succeeded in bringing attention to Dr. Coley's work by putting together case studies, publishing monographs, advocating this treatment to doctors and patients, and raising and disbursing funds for cancer research. In the process, Nauts served as executive director of the Cancer Research Institute from 1953 to 1982 and remained actively involved in the organization until her death on January 2, 2001.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of patient files, correspondence, writings, subject files, and other materials documenting the careers of Helen Coley Nauts and her father, William Coley. The collection includes information regarding the use of "Coley toxins," a vaccine developed by Coley and promoted by Nauts, which has been used successfully in the treatment of cancer.
Cancer -- Immunotherapy; Cancer -- Research; Cancer -- Treatment; Coley, William Bradley, 1862-1936; Nauts, Helen C. (Helen Coley), 1907-2001; Cancer Research Institute (New York, N.Y.)
- Helen Coley Nauts Active Files, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Files in this series are arranged alphabetically and Nauts' folder headings have been retained. The inventory lists the names of the first and last folder in a box only.
  - A - American-Portuguese Biomedical Fund (Box 1)
  - American Society for Psychical Research, Inc. - Bacid (Box 2)
  - Bacteriocins - BeeKeePea: Fleming (Box 3)
  - Behind Sofa - Bone tumors Ewing's sarcoma (Box 4)
  - Bone Tumors: Osteo - Bonilla-Naar (Box 5)
  - Brucella abortus - Cancer organ: self help share (Box 6)
  - Cancer organ: self help - Chlorella (Box 7)
  - Chlorophyll and Ca - Cope (Box 8)
  - CoQ10 - Delmont Labs (Box 9)
  - Delmont Labs - Duran-Reynals, Dr. F. (Box 10)
  - Duration of toxin therapy - ferritin (Box 11)
  - Fever - geographic distribution of mortality of ca (Box 12)
  - Geographical distribution - Hastings Center (Box 13)
  - Hauschka, Dr. T. S. - Hoffman Laboratories (Box 14)
  - Hollingshead, A - hyperthermia-George Crile (Box 15)
  - Hyperthermia BSD Corp - Hyperthermia Hopwood, Larry (Box 16)
  - Hyperthermia: Hornback, Ned - hyperthemia: Bon Ardenne (Box 17)
  - Hyperthermia: Warsaw Group - Immunotherapy - Lay Press (Box 18)
  - Immunotherapy, international registry - Interferon meetings (Box 19)
  - Interferon: skurkovich - De Kam, Cornelius (Box 20)
  - Kampschmidt - Laparoscopy (Box 21)
  - Laryngectomees and lumpy cancer - leukoplakea (Box 22)
  - Lev, Meir - lymph node dissections (Box 23)
  - Lymphocyte: role in cancer immunity - macula degeneration (Box 24)
  - Maggots - Memorial Hospital and S. K. I. (Box 25)
  - Memory - mucus-producing ca (Box 26)
  - Stuart Mudd - Jessie T. Nicholson (Box 27)
  - Nicotinic acid - osteitis vibrosa cystica (Box 28)
  - Osteoarthritis - patients: grateful (II) (Box 29)
  - Patients grateful (III) - plant extracts (Box 30)
  - Plant extracts: Ukraine - psoriasis (Box 31)
  - Psychology - counseling and cancer patients - pyrogens (Box 32)
  - Pyrogens, endogenous - Rank, Dale (Box 33)
  - Ransberger, K - reticulum cell sarcoma (Box 34)
  - Reticuloendothelial system - Shafir, Michael (Box 35)
  - Shear, Dr. Murray - spleen (Box 36)
  - Splenectomy - Strander, Hans (Box 37)
  - Strauss - survival (Box 38)
  - Shwartzman - thymus (Box 39)
  - Thyroid - trace elements: selenium (Box 40)
  - Trace elements: selenium (China) - urea (Box 41)
  - Uremia and cancer - vitamin C and betaine (Box 42)
  - Vitamin C - Waisbren, Burton (Box 43)
  - Waisbren, Burton - yeast extracts-di luzio (Box 44)
  - Yeast extracts - Zwilling, Bruce [include index to alphabetical files] (Box 45)
  - Country Files [foreign correspondence]
    - Argentina - China (Box 46)
    - China - Finland (Box 47)
    - France - Italy (Box 48)
    - Japan - Yugoslavia (Box 49)
  - Djerassi, Isaac [mostly correspondence] (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous (probably files taken from the alphabetical run and should be interfiled) (Box 51–52)
  - Breast cancer
    - A - E (Box 53)
    - E - M (Box 54)
    - M-R (Box 55)
    - R-W (Box 56)
- William B. Coley Medical Files, Series II
  - Case Files
    - A - Beebe and Tracy (Box 57)
    - Beede - Braswell (Box 58)
    - Brenner - Cole (Box 59)
    - Coley's cases - Docking (Box 60)
    - Dodd's cases - F (Box 61)
    - Faden - giant cell data done (Box 62)
    - Gibbon - Hanson (Box 63)
    - Harding - infection data - series E (Box 64)
    - Infections: indices statistics intro - Kelly (Box 65)
    - Kessel - Lowry (Box 66)
    - Lujan - Mann (Box 67)
    - Mark - Meyer (Box 68)
    - Michael - Nauts (Box 69)
    - Nauts - Ochsners (Box 70)
    - O'Connor - Pugh (Box 71)
    - Preparations index - Runnels' case (Box 72)
    - S - Major Spencer's cass (Box 73)
    - Spiegel - toxins on conditions other than cancer (Box 74)
    - Toxins: directions - Wechter (Box 75)
    - Wehrly - Zdanowich (Box 76)
    - Index (Kidgie's) (Box 77)
    - Patient notebooks and Laboratory notebook (Box 82)
  - Preparations Files (Box 78–79, Box 83)
  - Background (Box 80–81)
- Cancer Research Institute Files, 1912-2000; Series III
  - Tracy X Formula, undated (Box 84)
  - Master copies of appeal letters, 1973, 1974, 1980-1986, 1989-[1993], undated (Box 84)
  - Donor addresses, 1996-1997 (Box 84)
  - Wright, Jane, 1988-1994, undated (Box 84)
  - Donor appeals, 1979-1982, 1994-1996 (Box 84)
  - Awards dinners, 1995-1997, 2000 (Box 84)
  - Other events, 1997 (Box 84)
  - Symposia, 1993, 1995, 1996, 1999 (Box 84)
  - Annual Reports, 1988-1995, 1998-2000, undated (Box 84)
  - The Cancer Research Institute Story, [1979] (Box 84)
  - Correspondence
    - Abelev, Garri I. (Moscow), 1976-1994 (Box 85)
    - Adler, Frank, 1969-1989 (Box 85)
    - Alexander, Peter, 1966-1983 (Box 85)
    - Amos, Bernard D., 1972-1992 (Box 85)
    - Baldwin, R. W., 1971-2000 (Box 85)
    - Benacerraf, Baruj, 1973-1983 (Box 85)
    - Boyse, Edward, 1972-1978 (Box 85)
    - Burchenal, Joseph H., 1968-1982 (Box 85)
    - Frei, Emil, 1979-1982 (Box 85)
    - Goldstein, Gideon, 1975 (Box 85)
    - Good, Robert A., 1970-1992 (Box 85)
    - Gross, Ludwik, 1983-1990 (Box 85)
    - Gutterman, Jordan, 1978-1986 (Box 85)
    - Halpern, Bernard, 1967-1976 (Box 85)
    - Hellström, Karl Erik, 1969-1981 (Box 85)
    - Holland, James F., 1975-1988 (Box 85)
    - Houghton, Alan, 1986-1990 (Box 85)
    - Israel, Lucien, 1977-1986 (Box 85)
    - Kirkwood, John, 1990-1992 (Box 85)
    - Klein, Edmund, 1969-1999 (Box 85)
    - Klein, George, 1972-1982 (Box 85)
    - Mackaness, George, 1969-1978 (Box 85)
    - Mathé, George, 1969-1984 (Box 85)
    - Moore, Malcolm, 1989 (Box 85)
    - Morton, Donald, 1970-1992 (Box 85)
    - Morton, Donald [reprints of articles], 1966-1976 (Box 85)
    - Nordeman, Jacques, 1998 (Box 85)
    - Nossal, Gustav, 1976-1986 (Box 85)
    - Oettgen, Herbert, 1970-1981 (Box 85)
    - Old, Lloyd [recent correspondence], 1986-1996 (Box 85)
    - Old, Lloyd [awards received], 1990 (Box 85)
    - Old, Lloyd [biography,curriculumvitae, resumé, 1977-1988 (Box 85)
    - Old, Lloyd [reprints of articles], 1964-1991 (Box 85)
    - Old, Lloyd [correspondence], 1959-1988 (Box 85)
    - Ovary, Zoltan, 1975-1980 (Box 85)
    - Pernis, Benvenuto, 1973-1992 (Box 85)
    - Riggins, H. McLeod [applications and reports], 1963-1966 (Box 85)
    - Riggins, H. McLeod [correspondence], 1953-1973 (Box 85)
    - Schreck, Robert, 1958-1971 (Box 86)
    - Shepard, David, 1980-1991 (Box 86)
    - Sommers, Sheldon, 1965-1970 (Box 86)
    - Sutow, Wataru, 1956-1962 (Box 86)
    - Weiss, David, 1991 (Box 86)
    - Westphal, Otto, 1976-1994 (Box 86)
    - Woodruff, Michael, 1978-1982 (Box 86)
  - Scientific Advisory Council
    - Membership list, 1971, 1975, 1976, 1991 (Box 86)
    - Nobel prize winners, 1987 (Box 86)
    - Obituary for Peter Gorer, 1961 (Box 86)
    - Consent forms, 1975 (Box 86)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1989 (Box 86)
    - Former Council members, 1973 (Box 86)
    - Refusals of invitation to join Council, 1951-1969 (Box 86)
    - Inactive [G-Z], 1943-1970 (Box 86)
  - Trustees
    - Current, various, 1968-1995 (Box 87)
    - Arpels, Claude, 1976-1990 (Box 87)
    - Bales, Carter, 1976-1985 (Box 87)
    - Berner, Edgar, 1978-1994 (Box 87)
    - Blinderman, Abraham, 1977 (Box 87)
    - Boon, Thierry, 1993 (Box 87)
    - Curtis, Julia, 1988-1993 (Box 87)
    - Davidson, Stuart, 1992-1995 (Box 87)
    - Englund, Richard Bernard, 1991-1994 (Box 87)
    - Englund, Mr. And Mrs. Richard, 1979-1983 (Box 87)
    - French, Sally, 1991 (Box 87)
    - Friedman, Wilbur, 1990 (Box 87)
    - Fuller, Buckminster, 1964-1983 (Box 87)
    - Gogel, Donald, 1991-1993 (Box 87)
    - Glenn, Lynn, 1978-1994 (Box 87)
    - Green, Joyce, 1981-1982 (Box 87)
    - Green, Roger, 1976-1986 (Box 87)
    - Johnson, Thomas, 1991-1993 (Box 87)
    - Kellen, Anna Marie, 1978-1995 (Box 87)
    - Kennedy, Teddy, 1973-1974 (Box 87)
    - Kinney, David, 1984-1989 (Box 87)
    - Lasker, Mary, 1994 (Box 87)
    - Murray, William, 1974-1995 (Box 87)
    - Nordeman, Jacques, 1987-1992 (Box 87)
    - Rittereiser, Robert, 1983 (Box 87)
    - Robertson, Julian, 1974-1994 (Box 87)
    - Teller, Joseph, 1970-1973 (Box 87)
    - Villard, Dmitri, 1978 (Box 87)
    - Warner, Donald, 1961-1975 (Box 87)
    - Warner, Rawleigh, 1976 (Box 87)
    - Membership lists, 1976-1993 (Box 87)
    - Honorary trustees, 1967-1984 (Box 87)
    - Williams, C. Dickerman, 1957-1995 (Box 87)
    - CRI correspondence, 1995 (Box 87)
    - Trustees resigned or not reappointed, 1953-1978 (Box 87)
    - Trustees asked to serve, 1953-1978 (Box 87)
    - Formertrustees (two folders), 1953-1979 (Box 87)
    - Trustees, 1976-1989 (Box 87)
    - Grace, Oliver, 1954-1992 (Box 87)
    - Grace, Oliver, India House Luncheon, 1957 (Box 87)
    - Grace, Oliver, correspondence, 1953-1969 (Box 87)
  - CRI workshops and symposia
    - Monoclonal Antibodies and Cancer Therapy, 1995 (Box 87)
    - Vaccines, 1994 (Box 87)
    - Systemic Hyperthermia Oncological Working Group [SHOWG], 1994 (Box 87)
    - From Coley's Toxins to Recombinant Cytokines, 1994 (Box 87)
    - Frontiers of Immunology and Cancer Immunology, 1993 (Box 87)
    - Superantigens, 1993 (Box 87)
    - Genetic Manipulation of Tumor Immunity, 1992 (Box 87)
    - Molecular and Cellular Biology of Antigen Processing and Presentation, 1991 (Box 87)
    - Molecular Aspects of B Cell Differentiation, 1991 (Box 87)
    - Cellular Routes of Antigen Processing and Presentation, 1989 (Box 87)
    - Lymphotoxin, Tumor Necrosis Factor, and T, NK and Macrophage Cytotoxic Factors, 1984 (Box 87)
    - Origins of Inbred Mice Awards Ceremony, 1978 (Box 87)
  - Fellowships
    - Japanese Fellows, 1982 (Box 87)
    - Fellowships awarded, 1990-1991 (Box 87)
    - Applications list, 1991 (Box 87)
    - Applications list and recipient list, 1992 (Box 87)
    - Recipient list, 1994 (Box 87)
    - Fellows bibliography, 1975 (Box 87)
    - Fellowship application request, 1989 (Box 87)
    - Fellowships awarded, 1995 (Box 87)
    - Recipient list, 1993 (Box 87)
  - Awards ceremonies
    - Award dinners (two folders), 1975-1995 (Box 87)
    - Investigator awards, 1992 (Box 87)
    - Press release, 1979 (Box 87)
    - Awards in Cancer Immunology, 1979 (Box 87)
    - Awardee replies, 1979 (Box 87)
    - Thirtieth anniversary dinner, 1983 (Box 87)
    - Award jury, 1974 (Box 87)
    - Award suggestions, 1975 (Box 88)
  - CRI History
    - American Cancer Society Breast Conference [Helen Coley Nauts refused admission], 1979-1983 (Box 88)
    - Immunobiology Fellowship Training Program Comprehensive Progress Report, 1980 (Box 88)
    - Cancer research, miscellaneous, 1914-1995 (Box 88)
    - Financial statements and audits, 1988-1992 (Box 88)
    - Post office, 1974-1982 (Box 88)
    - Schering Corporation, 1944-1949 (Box 88)
    - Seed money, grants, [1977] (Box 88)
    - Publications, [1973]-1994 (Box 88)
    - Annual report, 1976 (Box 88)
    - The CRI Story, 1975 (Box 88)
    - Sample publications, 1984, undated (Box 88)
    - Childhood Cancer Research Institute, 1989-1992 (Box 88)
    - Early history (two folders), 1912-1989 (Box 88)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson and incorporation, 1953 (Box 88)
    - Bills, 1973-1976 (Box 88)
    - Reports, 1973-1975 (Box 88)
    - Coley, Ott Associates, 1973, 1974 (Box 88)
    - Coley, Ott correspondence, 1973, 1974 (Box 88)
    - Eddy, Harold, first CRI treasurer, 1953-1954 (Box 88)
    - Pros and cons of toxin therapy, 1949-1952 (Box 88)
    - Spencer, Oliver, 1966-1975 (Box 89)
    - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1973-1978 (Box 89)
    - First appeal booklet, 1953 (Box 89)
    - Clinical studies, 1972-1990 (Box 89)
    - Excerpts of pre-founding letters, 1953 (Box 89)
    - Financial totals, 1953-1976 (Box 89)
    - Struggles, 1952, 1953 (Box 89)
    - Appeal material, 1953-1954 (Box 89)
    - Appeals, 1953-1958 (Box 89)
    - Studdiford, William, attempts to publish first monograph, 1951-1952 (Box 89)
    - Publishing problems, 1951-1953 (Box 89)
    - Policy statement prior to 1963, 1954-1955 (Box 89)
    - Jackson, T. M., "Toxins for the Poor", 1990 (Box 89)
    - Sylvana Laboratories, 1970 (Box 89)
    - Nutrition, 1981 (Box 89)
    - Progress reports (three folders), 1959-1979 (Box 89)
    - Science, 1984 (Box 89)
    - American Way, 1986 (Box 89)
    - Raven Press, 1978 (Box 89)
    - Report on office procedure, 1976 (Box 89)
    - Vitamin list, 1982 (Box 89)
    - Obsolete nutrition, 1989 (Box 89)
    - Salaries, 1977-1981 (Box 89)
    - Compu Comp and typefaces, 1975-1980 (Box 89)
    - Duncan, John and notes on incorporation, 1953-1960 (Box 89)
    - Old address book, [195-]-[196-] (Box 89)
    - Miscellaneous history (two folders), 1945-1995 (Box 89)
- Helen Coley Nauts Family Papers, Series IV
  - Biographical and conference
    - Coley Toxings: Awards & Honors for W.B. Coley, 1980 October 27-29 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Coley Toxins: American Cancer Society & "Coley Methods" MOSS Letter, 1977 March 24 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Coley Toxins: Biography WBC [Brief Bio = 1 page], Undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Coley Toxins: Biography CRI Writers, 1966 December 12 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Coley Toxins: Biography [CRI] WBC EDITORS ASSESSMENT (Finnie, Gollin, Lewis, Williams, Fearing, etal.), 1992 June 17 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Coley Toxins: Centennial Spring,1993, 1993 June (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Coley Toxins: Death of WB Coley, 1996 April 12 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Coley Toxins: Directions for Administering Mixed Bac. Vacs., 1981 May 15 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Coley Toxins: Int'l Cancer Conference (attended by WB Coley, Ewing, Beebe 1910), 1909 January 2 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Coley Toxins: Macrophage & Cancer (Fidler, Klausner, et al), 1989 -1990 (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Coley Toxins: Nobel Prize, 1915 April 19 (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - Coley Toxins: Pioneer, As a, 1968 August 5 (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Coley Toxins: Quotes re/by WB Coley, 1891 (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Coley Toxins: Seminar/MSKCC re: Lymphoma, Undated (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Coley Toxins: Toxin Policy [CRI] [Circa 1960] (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Coley Toxins: Letter about WBC..., 1950-1992 (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - Coley Toxins: TNF Tumor Necrosis Factor, 1989 December 6 (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Coley Toxins: Toxins Refusals (MDs refused Coley Toxins), 1953 October 9 (Box 90, Folder 18)
    - Coley Toxins: Yale Medical School Library, 1978 June 27 (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - Loose materials re: HCN, 1997 April 2 (Box 90, Folder 20)
    - Nauts. Bio Letter: re Breast Book, 1982 October 29 (Box 90, Folder 21)
    - Nauts: Bio Articles re: HC Nauts [Mag, nwsppers, etc Not pub. by CRI], 1991 (Box 90, Folder 22)
    - Nauts: Bio Awards &/or Presentations, 1944-1986 (Box 90, Folder 23)
    - Nauts: Bio Index to files, 1996 March 8 (Box 90, Folder 24)
    - Nauts: Bio Articles re: HC Nauts by CRI, 1995 (Box 90, Folder 25)
    - Nauts: Bio Early CRI History as relates to writing of HCN Biography, 1972 May 20 (Box 90, Folder 27)
    - Nauts: Bio William B. Coley [References to/comments by re: only HCN Bio], 1933 January 25 (Box 90, Folder 28)
    - Nauts: Bio Articles by HC nauts [Not including Papers Read at Confers], 1996 February (Box 90, Folder 29)
    - Nauts: Bio "For My Bio" [Articles by others about other topics], 1996 February (Box 90, Folder 30)
    - Nauts: Bio China Trip, Undated (Box 90, Folder 31)
    - Nauts: Bio Coley, Bradley L. (brother) [only w/ regards NCH Bio], 1946 July 18-1955 September 16 (Box 90, Folder 32)
    - Nauts: Bio Coley Toxins [References in context only of HC Nauts Bio], 1947 August 12-1976 (Box 90, Folder 33)
    - Nauts: Bio Conferences Attended [outlined chart & details re: Papers], Undated (Box 90, Folder 34)
    - Nauts: Bio Family Related Articles [newspapers, etc. Not: BLC or WBC], 1979 February 22-1990 April 7-9 (Box 90, Folder 35)
    - Nauts: Bio Family Related Letters [not including BLC or WBC], 1894 January 5-1977 April 5 (Box 90, Folder 36)
    - Nauts: Bio Historical Articles [Bkgrd & Back-drop ofr HCN Bio only], 1944-1996 February 4 (Box 90, Folder 37)
    - Nauts: Bio Letters from/to Others to use in HCN Bio only, 1953 July 28-1996 February 22 (Box 90, Folder 38)
    - Nauts: Bio Publishers for HCN Biog, 1994 May 1-1994 July 19 (Box 90, Folder 39)
    - Nauts: Bio Letters from Grateful Patients, 1976 December 11-1978 February 21 (Box 90, Folder 40)
    - Nauts: Bio Letters to Newspapers from HCN, 1968 February 7-1985 October 18 (Box 90, Folder 41)
    - Nauts: Bio Letters: Praise [not re Breast Book] [not from patients], 1951 November 15-1994 May 4 (Box 90, Folder 42)
    - Nauts: Bio Monographs & Manuscripts, 1971-1995 (Box 90, Folder 43)
    - Nauts: Bio Papers Read [At US & International Sym/Conferences], Undated (Box 90, Folder 44)
    - Nauts: Bio Photographs, 1979-1982 (Box 90, Folder 45)
    - Nauts: Bio Quotes, Undated (Box 90, Folder 46)
    - Nauts: Bio Remininces, 1995 February 20-1995 January 26 (Box 90, Folder 47)
    - Nauts: Bio Slides, 1977-1982 (Box 90, Folder 48)
    - Nauts: Bio Speeches - by HCN & - about HCN, 1983-1988 (Box 90, Folder 49)
    - Nauts: Bio Talks: Miscellaneous [other than Papers Read/Conferences], 1987 March 9 (Box 90, Folder 50)
    - Nauts: Bio 30th Anniversary CRI - Letters - Speeches By & About HCN, 1975 October 29-1985 September 26 (Box 90, Folder 51)
    - Nauts: Bio TV [Brooklyn 1980] (Box 90, Folder 52)
    - Conference: 1980 Simonton: Conference/Workshop 1980, 1980 October 1 (Box 90, Folder 53)
    - Conference: 1979 ACS Breast "They wouldn't let me attend.", 1979 September 6-8 (Box 90, Folder 54)
    - Conference: 1979 6th Annual Breast Cancer Symposium NY Metropolitan Breast Cancer Group, 1979 January 20 (Box 90, Folder 55)
    - Conferernce: 1979 Inbread Mouse Awards Washington, DC, 1979 March 8 (Box 90, Folder 56)
    - Conference: 1977 Immunotherapy of Human Cancer Houston, 1977 November 9-11 (Box 90, Folder 57)
    - Conference: 1977 Hypoxic Cell Sensitizers Conference [Hyperthermia Conference Madison Wisconsin], 1977 October 13 (Box 90, Folder 58)
  - Diaries and miscellaneous (Box 91)
  - Unpublished writings (Box 92–93)
  - Misc (includes Helen, CRI, and Coley Family) (Box 94)
- William B. Coley Work Files and Family Papers, Series V
  - Files for book (four boxes to eventually be interfiled) (Box 95–98)
  - Helen's personal correspondence (to be reviewed with Phyllis Nauts) (Box 99)
  - William B. Coley (journals, correspondence, experiment data; 101 closed) (Box 100–101, Box 101A–101B)
  - General (includes multiple family members and William Coley professional/medical files) (Box 102–109)
- Writings and Miscellaneous, Series VI
  - Helen Coley and William B. Coley published writings and miscellaneous files found by Kidgie Williams (Box 110, Box 112–116)
    - "Bibliography (Annotated) of The Work of William B. Coley, M.D.", 2001 January (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1891-1894, 1891 September - 1895 January 5 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1895-1899, 1895 January 19 - 1899 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1901-1902, 1901 May - 1902 August (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1903, 1903 March 21 - 1903 July 25 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1905-1906, 1905 August - 1906 April (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1907 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Published writings of WBC (compiled), 1908, 1908 July (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1908-1909, 1908 September - 1909 November (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1910-1911, 1910 January 29 - 1911 August (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1912, 1912 January 6 - 1912 July (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1913-1915, 1913 March - 1915 September (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1916 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1917-1920, 1917 April 19 - 1920 August (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1921-1925, 1921 May - 1925 March (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1926-1927, 1926 March 15 - 1927 August (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1928-1929, 1928 October - 1929 November 15 (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1931-1934, 1931 January - 1934 February 15 (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - Published writings of WBC, 1935-1936, 1935 January - 1936 August (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - Published writings of WBC, undated (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Flyer for WBC lecture + synopsis, 1935, 1935 May - 1935 October (Box 111, Folder 21)